<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>a log on somersaulting</title>
    <link>/log/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Log on to oblique lair</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
        <atom:link href="/log/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Decadent Lethargy</title>
      <link>/decadent-lethargy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 07:24:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/decadent-lethargy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edited one or two lines in the &lt;a href=&#34;/support/&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a page, called &lt;a href=&#34;/di-why/&#34;&gt;Ideas of Possible Projects&lt;/a&gt;, where such list is found.
Right now, the page can be accessed through the Support page, this log, and by memory (adding &lt;code&gt;/di-why&lt;/code&gt; at the end of the base URL).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Dan Luu&amp;rsquo;s blog as another inspiration for this &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;Site&lt;/a&gt;.
Also added a service for those who may want to subscribe to RSS by email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the site&amp;rsquo;s logo to something&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;larger&lt;/em&gt;.
I used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://100r.co/site/dotgrid.html&#34;&gt;Hundred Rabbit&amp;rsquo;s Dotgrid&lt;/a&gt; tool to create it, which in my opinion is great!
Expect that I will play with drawing software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the Index, my CV can now be viewed as a page in this website without having to donwload the PDF.
I also updated a line in the footer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s getting harder to focus one one thing at a time in this Age of Information.
I know, because I suffer from the same problem day in and day out.
Not much to it, really.
I use the term &amp;ldquo;suffer&amp;rdquo; but it feels more like decadent lethargy.
&lt;em&gt;If you can do the same thing with less effort, do it!&lt;/em&gt;
I often tell myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same vein, could being lazy, and possibly helping others settle into their own brand of Laziness, be a career path?
Of course, it has to be rebranded, like:
&lt;strong&gt;Help people get the most useful {info, thing, experience, XYZ} in the shortest time possible.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep on reading and hearing about this Pomodoro technique for years now.
Perhaps, it&amp;rsquo;s a viable solution to my waning and waxing attention span.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperconnectivity allows us to access different people, different stuff from different points most of the time, and yet it can&amp;rsquo;t necessarily nourish us.
Is it more likely that it instead drains us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is March now.
Heat starts to become unbearable.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to have an aircon unit in our room, and today it is now installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who would have thought that we&amp;rsquo;re nearing the anniversary of a lockdown?
To commemorate this wonderful event, we&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded Katamari Damacy on Isya&amp;rsquo;s old/new laptop.
I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of completing the game 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redistribution</title>
      <link>/redis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 11:59:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/redis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new sections to the &lt;a href=&#34;/server/&#34;&gt;Server&lt;/a&gt; project.
Still haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to it, but I will soon.
I have to, now that I have a domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Paypal link in my &lt;a href=&#34;/support/&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; page.
Also inserted a better pitch in there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edited a footnote in the &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;Site&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor edit of the footer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a society much better than this one, many things are readily available to everyone.
People meet their basic needs.
I imagine they are freer in their actions, in that they don&amp;rsquo;t (need/feel the need to) limit others&#39; freedoms.
But this isn&amp;rsquo;t that society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, support the people you want and can, in any method, legal and/or moral, you know how.
&lt;em&gt;Redistribute&lt;/em&gt; everything else accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Want a Maggot-Free Cake</title>
      <link>/cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 08:05:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a way for readers (are there any?) to support me, found in this page: &lt;a href=&#34;/support/&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; (via Liberapay).
To be as less obnoxious about it as possible, this link will only be at the end of each Project page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed my email address in the Index.
After getting a domain from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epik.com&#34;&gt;Epik&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s registrar and setting up an email server with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.migadu.com&#34;&gt;Migadu&lt;/a&gt;, I now have a custom email address.
In the future, I will also set one up for Isya.
In the meantime, please send your mails to my new address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also in Index, edited a few lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, our neighbors gifted us with plenty of food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One gave a tofu-version of sisig.
This lady was delighted to know that too I&amp;rsquo;m a tofu fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another neighbor brought us &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; different servings of food:
chocolate cake and macaroni fruit salad.
The latter we found weird&amp;mdash;who adds macaroni in fruit salads?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cake&amp;mdash;the cake is a lie.
Good thing that Isya first inspected it before eating a slice.
The cake is full of maggots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to throw it out, and by that I mean send it to the compost bin.
Give it one last purpose, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, that we&amp;rsquo;ve been primed to desire a chocolate cake, ordering one, maggot-free, was the next most logical step.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>積ん読</title>
      <link>/tsundoku/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 15:05:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tsundoku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the CV. Reduced it to one page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the status of &lt;a href=&#34;/encode/&#34;&gt;Encoding&lt;/a&gt; project
from &lt;strong&gt;on-going&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;done&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/l/?uddg=https%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FTsundoku&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tsundoku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (積ん読) becomes our mode of expressing ourselves here.
How we decorate the blank spaces with books of various interests.
It&amp;rsquo;s because the many books that we acquire that we have not touched and are piled up together are for sale at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;alwayscarry.netlify.app&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always Carry A Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a mantra that we follow only when it&amp;rsquo;s convenient, and less than one kilogram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can only gloss over them as we put them up on the store one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the many more books that already have that aren&amp;rsquo;t for sale, well, they shall remain dusty until we find time to pick them up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pressing Issues on a Valentine&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>/piv-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 07:24:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/piv-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a site logo.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually just scaled vector graphics (SVG) coded with HTML.
Experimental at the moment.
I&amp;rsquo;ll likely change that into something more artsy in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edited a few lines in the &lt;a href=&#34;/encode/&#34;&gt;Encoding&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edited some parts in &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;This Site&lt;/a&gt; project.
I added some notes about my new found tool, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jarun/imgp&#34;&gt;imgp&lt;/a&gt;, with the help of which I&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;redid an image in &lt;a href=&#34;/mercipod/&#34;&gt;iPod Upgrade&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the @tuta.io email from Index.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I can&amp;rsquo;t access Tutanota servers.
Something to do with my location?
In the meantime, @live.com.ph shall receive any emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A day like any other.
An okay day so far for a cat named Ming to look for love (or escape from hate) beyond the walls.
A perfect time to be hounded by pressing questions like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the realistic thing to do to not go hungry and be kicked out in the streets?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern answer: Get a job.
I prefer &amp;ldquo;At least be useful to people,&amp;rdquo; but to be honest, consistently doing that takes effort and leads to burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not at all a bad day, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a non-exhaustive list of what a bad day looks likes.
I like making lists.
Creating lists has a calming effect.
Anyway, specify a number of items in the list, that when met, will constitute a bad day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is also a great day to go against the grain, to have the guts to think independently of what&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;uso&lt;/em&gt;.
Some might suspect its edginess, but as long as hate isn&amp;rsquo;t promoted, it&amp;rsquo;s fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose a simple set of tunes to spaghettify to &lt;em&gt;en plein air&lt;/em&gt;, even if it&amp;rsquo;s unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Habit: Impatience</title>
      <link>/badimp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 07:31:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/badimp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworked the color of blockquotes on a dark-themed system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added background color to footnote (back) reference links, so they can be easily distinguished.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a few emojis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have long since acknowledged my terri(ble/fic) demeanor.
I am (im)patient, it goes without saying, and I have to check myself constantly before doing something or opening my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have become more irritable towards myself, because of the petty mistakes that most likely go into flames, which I would then fan.&lt;br&gt;
No one should sustain this habit of self-depracating.
I know it&amp;rsquo;s unhealthy, and yet I do it, like eating fried meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society as a whole likes to drone over the shoulder to peek at the things I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be doing but don&amp;rsquo;t.
Sometimes, it seems disappointed, but mostly, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;br&gt;
They don&amp;rsquo;t care in the sense that they can&amp;rsquo;t;
they don&amp;rsquo;t know me at all, so there&amp;rsquo;s really no big reason to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Author to be laid off</title>
      <link>/nowork/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 01:14:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nowork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new project &lt;a href=&#34;/mercipod/&#34;&gt;iPod Classic Hard Drive Upgrade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor adjustments in fonts and their sizes.
Does it improve the readability of the site?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk briefly about my current employment situation, which would end soon:
I would be officially out of work by this 12 Feb, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s fine.
An official excuse to be lethargic for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing is lined up at the momment.
The search goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just that employers make sure that they do as much filtering as possible.
Some would inappropriately ask, &amp;ldquo;What self-improvement did you do during the lockdown?&amp;rdquo;
What they&amp;rsquo;re really asking is, &amp;ldquo;We are looking for people with the initiative to make themselves useful for profit-making. Are you one of them?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People need to slow down.
Don&amp;rsquo;t give in to the hustle culture, which is inherently toxic by nature anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Pagkakaisa</title>
      <link>/pagkakaisa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 11:55:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pagkakaisa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed a few sentences in &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;This Site&lt;/a&gt;, particularly those about my implied distaste towards JS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After more than a year of not making an appearance in our ancestral house in Pagkakaisa Street, Isya and I finally went there yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I was not too excited on going there for a number of things.
First, commuting via public transportation from Antipolo to Makati, even on a Sunday, is not easy.
Our travel time lasted around two hours, one way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lastly, people there, my relatives, are heavy chain-smokers.
Perhaps, the next time that we&amp;rsquo;ll be there, we should wear (gas) masks indoors.
The smokescreen from their constantly burning cigarettes was so thick I could not see past an arm&amp;rsquo;s length.
I wish I was exagerrating.
Let&amp;rsquo;s not even go to how long that toxic fume sticks on your person.
Hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there we went, with or without incentives, because it&amp;rsquo;s been more than a year since I saw them.
We have more catching up to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esmeris Farm</title>
      <link>/esmeris/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 15:16:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/esmeris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/esmeris.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;foliage, forest&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Imagine being surrounded by this&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that I was present the entire trip from Rizal to Laguna and back, that&amp;rsquo;s why I only manage to take a few photos.
In reality, the trip exhausted me and my companions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s literally a needed trip.
Each of us had expected something out of this, but it&amp;rsquo;s unclear whether we&amp;rsquo;re all okay with the outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentimental music in city pop always puts me in place, especially when the setting blows cold, wet winds our way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Future will be chilling long after it has burned.
Every notion will have become useless by then, but it the meantime, any idea is worth arguing for so long as it makes perfect sense to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No New Interesting</title>
      <link>/nonew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 10:13:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nonew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed this site&amp;rsquo;s title, from &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;of somersaulting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;to oblique lair&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.
The latter is an anagram of my middle and surname.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that it emits a certain mystery that kind of misleads.
If that sounds like equine shite, maybe because it is.
Look up &amp;ldquo;anagram maker&amp;rdquo; on your favorite search engine if you&amp;rsquo;re into that kind of fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some new recommendations in the &lt;a href=&#34;/encode/&#34;&gt;Encoding&lt;/a&gt; project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edited some lines and addded footnotes in &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;This Site&lt;/a&gt; project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New CSS for &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; blocks using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/syntax-highlighting/&#34;&gt;Hugo&amp;rsquo;s built-in syntax highlighting&lt;/a&gt;.
Currently, I am using the &lt;code&gt;monokai&lt;/code&gt; theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new section in &lt;a href=&#34;/alwayscarry/&#34;&gt;Always Carry A Book Website&lt;/a&gt; project that briefly explains about a newly added search function feature using JavaScript. 😨&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated my CV using Pandoc.
It is now two pages long, so I may have to readjust the margins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is mostly changelog that I decided to post because this list is getting long enough.
No new interesting narratives for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, tomorrow, we scheduled a trip to Liliw.
We hope to see waterfalls and trees.
Maybe I can share some photo/s in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, it would be my first long trip since the Pandemic started, and outside the capital at that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Life Hacks</title>
      <link>/lh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 01:44:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new project: &lt;a href=&#34;/encode/&#34;&gt;Encoding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some lines in &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;This Site&lt;/a&gt; project, expounding more on the use of Hugo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lower&amp;mdash;or, better yet, &lt;em&gt;eliminate&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;expectations.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;Wag (masyadong) umasa.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t use social media.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Iwasan na ang social media.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;100 grams of dry pasta per person; 1 teaspoon of salt per liter of pasta water.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;100 gramong pasta kada tao; 1 kutsaritang asin kada litro ng pinagpakuluan ng pasta.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t have kids.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Wag nang mag-anak.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to be honest with yourself.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Maging tapat sa sarili.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to make time for your loved ones.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Wag mong kalimutang maglaan ng oras para sa iyong mga minamahal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember your loved ones, no matter where or when they are.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ano bang alam ko kundi ang mangulila?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that the mask goes over the nose.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tandaan na dapat matakpan ng face mask ang ilong.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causing Headaches</title>
      <link>/headache/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 19:24:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/headache/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new sections to the &lt;a href=&#34;/alwayscarry/&#34;&gt;Always Carry A Book Website&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor edit on the footer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some blurbs on the Index, like adding a separate email for work-related stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edited title for &lt;a href=&#34;/log/index.xml&#34;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that I&amp;rsquo;m taking it easy.
By having some personal projects that I enjoy doing, going through the motions of the day becomes mentally stimulating.
To be honest, I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself monetizing a side project any time soon.
But, anytime soon, that could change because of some interjection of Randomness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe in these small pursuits I won&amp;rsquo;t affect anything.
At least I can give &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt; a headache by not merely doing what they think I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Old</title>
      <link>/grow-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 20:55:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/grow-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listed new project: &lt;a href=&#34;/alwayscarry/&#34;&gt;Always Carry A Book website&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s currently under construction, but feel free to check either the post, or the website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed background color of a blockquote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed some wording in &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;This Site&lt;/a&gt; project, something about my opinion on not having JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hirap tumanda.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s already evening as I type this out.
Just got home from Isya&amp;rsquo;s Inay&amp;rsquo;s home in Marikina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ate Emelyn (not sure of the spelling or if I heard it right) and I prepared the lunch.
According to survey, the food was good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to grow old?
Does it mean wisdom?
Does it mean forfeiting everyday human function in order to live longer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impatience of one elderly seems to ripple to every person trying to take care of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bless all the caretakers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crises and New Fear</title>
      <link>/canf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 13:48:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/canf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No major updates for this site.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t been doing anything lately for research.
Of course, here, &amp;ldquo;research&amp;rdquo; is what I call it.
Essentially, it&amp;rsquo;s me doing a deep dive into things that I&amp;rsquo;m currently interested in doing.
I may have already said that somewhere here before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be &amp;ldquo;looking for new opportunities&amp;rdquo; very soon.
In the interim, I have to ask myself how best to use my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I have installed a Debian-based distro in my machine.
The previous one, an Arch-based, acted up on a major update, and many things stopped working completely.
So much for trusting &amp;ldquo;bleeding edge.&amp;rdquo;
Good thing that most of the important things, including this blog&amp;rsquo;s files, are backed up safely somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is our suffering that brings us together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A line that I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://libcom.org/library/dispossessed-ursula-le-guin&#34;&gt;somewhere&lt;/a&gt;.
Which would ring true forevermore, except if nirvana is achieved.
And will that come, even a lesser version of it?
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine to get lighter as we see the world as it is today,
with all of its supposed leaders continuously disappointing the rest of us dispossessed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December Fugue</title>
      <link>/fugue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 22:46:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fugue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some lines and footnotes to &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;The Site&lt;/a&gt; project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new project: &lt;a href=&#34;/server/&#34;&gt;Own Web Server&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing there yet except a few lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor edit of blurb on landing page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added yet another item on to-do list for The Site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added color to status on &lt;a href=&#34;/project/&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many unwanted noise all around us.
It could be all ending soon, but there is no clue when.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holidays, unsurprisingly, are propelling people to go around and about, not minding the on-going pandemic.
Or perhaps, they do mind the risk;
it&amp;rsquo;s just that they&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to deal with it haphazardly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything seems to be back to normal, except this time, we now have to worry about getting COVID from anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything back to abnormal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solitude must be fought for nowadays, I think, or it will get drowned out by people who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t learn to be still, by things that won&amp;rsquo;t stop oscillating, and by the human mind that can&amp;rsquo;t settle with boredom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twilight World</title>
      <link>/tenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 19:56:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tenet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed (again) the Creative Commons licensing, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.
The addition here is &lt;em&gt;Share Alike&lt;/em&gt;.
The license still allows adaptations of my work to be shared, but this particular one &lt;em&gt;must be preserved&lt;/em&gt; during transit.
This should prevent others from copying/adapting my work &lt;em&gt;and then&lt;/em&gt; closing the free flow of information by slapping a different copyright license.
I also removed the icon.
All this nuisance, I hope that it matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added my CV in the &lt;a href=&#34;/&#34;&gt;Index&lt;/a&gt;, in case a prospective employer wanders in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new segments to &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;The Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the navigation menu. The major sections can be accessed in the Index, and at the end of each Page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we visited Isya&amp;rsquo;s Inay&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; yesterday in Marikina, the lunch was already waiting for us.
Beef pochero did us in, but only enough to go through another helping in the evening&amp;rsquo;s partaking.
More enriching was their rice, imported from Abra up north of Luzon.
I have to know what it&amp;rsquo;s called, so we can scout it from nearby rice suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We watched Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Tenet&lt;/em&gt; after lunch.
Actually, Isya and I had already seen it a few days prior;
we&amp;rsquo;re just rewatching this to hopefully answer some of our questions the movie&amp;rsquo;s convoluted plot.
As you may know, Nolan&amp;rsquo;s films require more than just one viewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Isya and I are planning to watch another Nolan&amp;rsquo;s, &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inay&lt;/em&gt; is their term of endearment for their paternal grandmother. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impostor Syndrome</title>
      <link>/impsyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 17:51:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/impsyn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the date format in Log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added another to-do for &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;The Site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now officially part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://512kb.club&#34;&gt;512 KB Club&lt;/a&gt;.
You&amp;rsquo;re now reminded of this in the footer, lol!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like a fraud for not having accomplished anything significant, but I need to constantly remind myself that in all the worlds that I&amp;rsquo;ve been in, it&amp;rsquo;s okay for anyone to choose taking it slow whenever they can here and now, in this 2020-version of the World.
However, I hope to transcend this slump, of course, with the help of my loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lethargy is only a useful excuse when &amp;ldquo;used&amp;rdquo; against the backdrop of the already oppressive systems in place.
I know this, because this is the only thing I&amp;rsquo;m still getting good at, even before the Pandemic has &amp;ldquo;locked down&amp;rdquo; people in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this I mean, I hope to contribute to the society at large by the microtansactions of&amp;hellip; kindness? of goodness? that I&amp;rsquo;m still capable of manifesting, if that makes sense.
Who knows, that could be an interesting research and development?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Rush</title>
      <link>/rush/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:05:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rush/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced the Creative Commons Licensing from &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.
If I were to advocate for free flow of information, I must let others, including commercial institutions, be able to riff off of my work.
I only ask that they include my name in the footnotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some new sections to &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;This Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the blurb on the landing page that said &amp;ldquo;I have no other social media accounts&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
That&amp;rsquo;s not really accurate.
What I don&amp;rsquo;t have are Facebook, Twitter, TikTok, and Instagram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &amp;ldquo;Last Update&amp;rdquo; logic in &lt;a href=&#34;/project/&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all learn that it takes a whole lot of time to get to know oneself.
A year&amp;rsquo;s worth of quasi-isolation seems to be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A flare of imagination could trigger emotions never felt before, and to that person, this is their first time learning this thing about himself.
It could be wild, sometimes&amp;ndash;detrimental, even&amp;ndash;to not have the full scope of one&amp;rsquo;s being at one&amp;rsquo;s disposal for one&amp;rsquo;s perusal.
That&amp;rsquo;s also one of the main reasons why I started this blog: another attempt to understand myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t really just say to ourselves, &amp;ldquo;Be patient,&amp;rdquo; because the systems laid out in front of us are designed to burn us out.
Besides, it&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to remain patient when I&amp;rsquo;m constantly facing external pressures to Do Something Productive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And now, for something completely different</title>
      <link>/nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:56:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/&#34;&gt;This site&lt;/a&gt; is now live, hosted for the meantime in &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also listed as a project. Learn more about the design philosophies &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured I needed to have an online presence again, one that I can call my own, far from the algorithms of major social networking sites.
But aside from that, the idea to have a personal site started when Isya, my partner, suggested that I continue with my post-graduate studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, I said, is that I no longer think it&amp;rsquo;s something worth pursuing anymore.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can stomach the academia life, not that it&amp;rsquo;s glamorous to begin with anyway.
Besides, life is more interesting in fields beyond engineering, my background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I played with the notion of publishing my personal projects (they&amp;rsquo;re not many) online for everyone to study, scrutinize, make better, etc.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see if this method is any better than formally enrolling in a university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, today&amp;rsquo;s is Bonifacio&amp;rsquo;s day.
Not only that, it&amp;rsquo;s my Tita Bonnie&amp;rsquo;s 61st birthday.
&lt;em&gt;Ano kaya ang handa nila?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>/hi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 14:25:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens from this point shall be defined by my Willpower, and how I manage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
