<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Log on of somersaulting</title>
    <link>/log/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Log on of somersaulting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
        <atom:link href="/log/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Impostor Syndrome</title>
      <link>/impsyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 17:51:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/impsyn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the date format in Log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added another to-do for &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;The Site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now officially part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://512kb.club&#34;&gt;512 KB Club&lt;/a&gt;.
You&amp;rsquo;re now reminded of this in the footer, lol!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like a fraud for not having accomplished anything significant, but I need to constantly remind myself that in all the worlds that I&amp;rsquo;ve been in, it&amp;rsquo;s okay for anyone to choose taking it slow whenever they can here and now, in this 2020-version of the World.
However, I hope to transcend this slump, of course, with the help of my loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lethargy is only a useful excuse when &amp;ldquo;used&amp;rdquo; against the backdrop of the already oppressive systems in place.
I know this, because this is the only thing I&amp;rsquo;m still getting good at, even before the Pandemic has &amp;ldquo;locked down&amp;rdquo; people in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this I mean, I hope to contribute to the society at large by the microtansactions of&amp;hellip; kindness? of goodness? that I&amp;rsquo;m still capable of manifesting, if that makes sense.
Who knows, that could be an interesting research and development?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Rush</title>
      <link>/rush/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:05:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rush/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced the Creative Commons Licensing from &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.
If I were to advocate for free flow of information, I must let others, including commercial institutions, be able to riff off of my work.
I only ask that they include my name in the footnotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some new sections to &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;This Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the blurb on the landing page that said &amp;ldquo;I have no other social media accounts&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
That&amp;rsquo;s not really accurate.
What I don&amp;rsquo;t have are Facebook, Twitter, TikTok, and Instagram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &amp;ldquo;Last Update&amp;rdquo; logic in Projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all learn that it takes a whole lot of time to get to know oneself.
A year&amp;rsquo;s worth of quasi-isolation seems to be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A flare of imagination could trigger emotions never felt before, and to that person, this is their first time learning this thing about himself.
It could be wild, sometimes&amp;ndash;detrimental, even&amp;ndash;to not have the full scope of one&amp;rsquo;s being at one&amp;rsquo;s disposal for one&amp;rsquo;s perusal.
That&amp;rsquo;s also one of the main reasons why I started this blog: another attempt to understand myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t really just say to ourselves, &amp;ldquo;Be patient,&amp;rdquo; because the systems laid out in front of us are designed to burn us out.
Besides, it&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to remain patient when I&amp;rsquo;m constantly facing external pressures to Do Something Productive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And now, for something completely different</title>
      <link>/nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:56:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/&#34;&gt;This site&lt;/a&gt; is now live, hosted for the meantime in &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also listed as a project. Learn more about the design philosophies &lt;a href=&#34;/site/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured I needed to have an online presence again, one that I can call my own, far from the algorithms of major social networking sites.
But aside from that, the idea to have a personal site started when Isya, my partner, suggested that I continue with my post-graduate studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, I said, is that I no longer think it&amp;rsquo;s something worth pursuing anymore.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can stomach the academia life, not that it&amp;rsquo;s glamorous to begin with anyway.
Besides, life is more interesting in fields beyond engineering, my background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I played with the notion of publishing my personal projects (they&amp;rsquo;re not many) online for everyone to study, scrutinize, make better, etc.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see if this method is any better than formally enrolling in a university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, today&amp;rsquo;s is Bonifacio&amp;rsquo;s day.
Not only that, it&amp;rsquo;s my Tita Bonnie&amp;rsquo;s 61st birthday.
&lt;em&gt;Ano kaya ang handa nila?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>/hi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 14:25:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens from this point shall be defined by my Willpower, and how I manage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
