<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on of somersaulting</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on of somersaulting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
        <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>This Site</title>
      <link>/site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status: On-going&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is itself a personal project, a documentation of other projects that I log here.
If we are to use modern internet terms, this is also a wiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;front-end&#34;&gt;Front-end&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you are well aware, this site has a very simple design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By foregoing intricate UI/UX design, I can focus on what matters most: &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt;.
Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By simplifying the design, I&amp;rsquo;m making this site less bloated.
This means that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;old computers with slow and outdated software can visit without hassle on their end;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;locations with slow internet connectivity can still browse the content;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can also improve this site&amp;rsquo;s accessibility by improving some functions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-end&#34;&gt;Back-end&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator to build this site.
There are many other big names out there, like Jekyll, Gatsby, Pelican, and Hexo, but I have no experience using them.
I have no particular reason why I chose Hugo, except maybe that it&amp;rsquo;s written in Go.
And some experts say that most software developed using a compiled language (which Go is) can be &amp;ldquo;blazing fast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-hugo&#34;&gt;Using Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of tutorials online on how to start a blog using Hugo.
A lot of them, if you follow to the letter, will set you up a nice content management system (CMS, a fancier term for blog).
But many of these tutorials are naturally targetted to beginners who just want to get something up already, and not go through hours of laboriously reading through the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want something that isn&amp;rsquo;t pre-fabricated, some template that can&amp;rsquo;t be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/a&gt;, a theme that speaks your personality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s when you need to read the docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, Hugo&amp;rsquo;s learning curve is steep, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re like me with no &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; coding experience.
Maybe it helps when you&amp;rsquo;ve been dealing with software programming for a while.
Your mileage may vary.
My process involves a lot of trial and error to get this site looking the way it is now, simple as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disabling-internal-templates&#34;&gt;Disabling Internal Templates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo ships with internal templates that I have disabled because they either violate privacy, will add unnecessary bloat to the site, or both. They are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disqus comments, a popular commenting system;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram cards;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter cards;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vimeo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have a privacy-centered configuration, I followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/&#34;&gt;this documentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/#disable-all-services&#34;&gt;disabled all services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in high school, I&amp;rsquo;m not the brightest pupil in our computer lab, and I&amp;rsquo;m okay with that.
One of our &amp;ldquo;lab works&amp;rdquo; was to create our own website.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how mine looked, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s basic, with broken links hither and thither.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a decade later, here I am, building one again.
At least I retained the important bits on how HTML works, so I&amp;rsquo;m not starting from zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to say that I dedicate this to my former self, who couldn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp the importance of web design.
Even today, I can only rely on Hugo, a working knowledge in HTML and CSS, and a little bit of patience to set everything up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some other sites from which I got inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low-tech Magazine, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com&#34;&gt;solar-powered one&lt;/a&gt;. Their article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2018/09/how-to-build-a-lowtech-website.html&#34;&gt;how to build a low-tech website&lt;/a&gt; is eye-opening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://1mb.club&#34;&gt;1MB Club&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s contemporaries, &lt;a href=&#34;https://512kb.club&#34;&gt;512KB Club&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://250kb.club&#34;&gt;250KB Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bestmotherfucking.website&#34;&gt;Best Motherfucking Website&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;digital-garden&#34;&gt;Digital Garden&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been looking around for personal websites like I have, &amp;ldquo;digital garden&amp;rdquo; is a phrase that gets used often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is where webmasters carefully plant the seeds of ideas, and hope to grow them sustainably.
It&amp;rsquo;s a more endearing term, I believe, than, say, a public-facing journal or simply blog.
They all function the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site, then, is my digital garden.
Expect that things will be corrected, deleted, edited, fed, &lt;em&gt;grown&lt;/em&gt;, depending on any number of factors, including the current state of things.
People change (they need to, lest they stagnate), and and every fiber of their being changes with them, literally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
