<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>a log on somersaulting</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on to oblique lair</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
        <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Imbentori: A Tumblr Blog</title>
      <link>/imbentori/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 11:59:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/imbentori/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;statusDone&#34; id=&#34;status-done&#34;&gt;Status: Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may or may not have been obvious, but people around my age are fond of expressing themselves on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was active in one platform which is still out there, on Tumblr, that you can still visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iooare.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;Imbentori&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is/was my Tumblr blog the password of which I no longer remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little while back, I even thought of parsing through the original text I have there, and publish them in some sort of a book&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not throwing this idea permanently away.
It&amp;rsquo;s just that I have more interesting things to tackle, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, read the foreword I drafted some time ago for this would-be collection of personal essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tongue that swirls with its perceived languages can only cope so much from the demands of diction.
&lt;em&gt;Imbentori&lt;/em&gt;, then, is one own&amp;rsquo;s tongue&amp;rsquo;s attempt to speak the library of tensions as they never unfold in one&amp;rsquo;s mind.
It is a list of personal truths told with cryptic lingo
(or with International Art English&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, one could argue)
to add dimension to the mundane.
In some entries, there&amp;rsquo;s no room for interpretation.
In any case, if you feel like the stream of thoughts challenge the way you read, &lt;em&gt;hmm&lt;/em&gt;, then it&amp;rsquo;s purpose didn&amp;rsquo;t go off tangent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Which is what, exactly?&amp;rdquo; I hear you ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well,&amp;rdquo; I mutter, racking my brain for &lt;em&gt;proper&lt;/em&gt; wording.
&amp;ldquo;The intention of sharing this version of my Youth&amp;mdash;captured between 2012 and 2018&amp;mdash;is to offer a perspective of someone who both despises the world, yet remains hopeful of the people&amp;rsquo;s capacity to kick-start a change, although they bore me at that.&amp;rdquo;
And then you plop back on your chair, still unsatisfied with my ambiguous response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will notice quirks.
One of the most notable was how I refuse to capitalize letters that needed capitalization.
It&amp;rsquo;s style;
you&amp;rsquo;ll get over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;theres-a-free-copy-online&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a free copy online&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of them are lumped into what I call &lt;a href=&#34;https://iooare.tumblr.com/tagged/unscholarly-notes&#34;&gt;Unscholarly Notes&lt;/a&gt;,
after a chapter in one of my favorite books by F. Sionil Jose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of a paper called &lt;a href=&#34;http://journal.sjdm.org/19/190712/jdm190712.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bullshit Makes The Art Grow Profounder&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Turpin et. al., 2019).
Some 20(20) years ago when I last visited an art museum (or was it just gallery?), I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but roll my eyes on a lot of pieces&#39; description cards that seemingly always include how the artist &amp;ldquo;explores&amp;rdquo; this or that. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPod Classic Hard Drive Upgrade</title>
      <link>/mercipod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 17:45:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mercipod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;statusDone&#34; id=&#34;status-done&#34;&gt;Status: Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Nay Merci, Isya&amp;rsquo;s mom, sent her iPod Classic&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to me for repair, a device that&amp;rsquo;s at least ten years old now.
It&amp;rsquo;s life can still be stretched by upgrading some of its components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2018, I did a similar upgrade on Isya&amp;rsquo;s iPod Classic, which I wrote about on &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; blog&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, so doing this isn&amp;rsquo;t something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the overview of what I did.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a step-by-step guide, and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be considered as such.
It&amp;rsquo;s merely an attempt to document the process through a crappy camera and poor lighting that I have.
Pardon the amateur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-what-i-need&#34;&gt;Getting what I need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I list the things needed to replace the orignal mechanical hard drive with the new, much faster, solid state drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi1.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;a spread of items needed to upgrade the ipod, including hard drive and prying tools&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;TOP HALF, LEFT TO RIGHT: iPod Classic, new microSD card, iFlash-Quad microSD adapter (and the included square foam below it), special flexible steel pry bar; BOTTOM HALF: an assortment of prying tools&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;iflash-quad&#34;&gt;iFlash-Quad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iflash.xyz&#34;&gt;iFlash&lt;/a&gt; is the go-to site/store when it comes to iPod adapters.
They have adapters that will fit iPod Videos, iPod Classics, and iPod Photos.
The iFlash site has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iflash.xyz/helpful-tips-and-advice/&#34;&gt;helpful tips and advice&lt;/a&gt; for non-pro iPod modders like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when there was a slight problem in shipping (probably due the on-going Pandemic), the iFlash team was quick to resolve the problem, at no extra cost.
Great customer service, if you ask me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iFlash-Quad is, in my opinion, the best bang-for-buck purchase for this iPod.
Good capacity is 256Gb to 1Tb!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From their site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatic quad mode adapter&amp;mdash;use with 1 MicroSD card in standard mode, and  2, 3, or 4 MicroSD cards in mixed JBOD (Just a Bunch Of Disks) mode for even greater storage capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mix and Match any MicroSD cards, you are free to mix any size and any brand to achieve your iPod needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligent power management with much lower power consumption than the original Hard drive, longer runtimes and quicker user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true.
I&amp;rsquo;ve done this in Isya&amp;rsquo;s iPod, and it has worked better since its upgraded.
So I know it will improve &amp;lsquo;Nay Merci&amp;rsquo;s iPod, which I&amp;rsquo;ll unofficially call Mercipod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;microsd-cards&#34;&gt;MicroSD Cards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maximum of four.
This will vary on how hardcore of a music enthusiast you are, and/or your budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re aiming for 1Tb worth of music, it might well be a replacement for your Spotify!
It&amp;rsquo;s offline, too, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need internet connection to play music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you have some familiarity with iPods and how they need to interface with iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, when we connect the iPod to a computer with iTunes on it, the iTunes will be the one to put music on it, by syncing the library with the iPod.
So, don&amp;rsquo;t put your mp3 files in the microSD just yet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prying-tools&#34;&gt;Prying tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any Apple device, iPod is tricky to open.
Classic Apple move discourages the owners to repair their own devices through malicious design and planned obsolescence, but it&amp;rsquo;s a discussion for another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One special tool is the flexible steel pry bar tool.
It&amp;rsquo;s a thin steel with grip, ideal for opening iPods.
iFlash offers it in their store.
Another brand, iSesamo, is known to be the gold standard for prying open iPods, but you may find it a bit too pricey, especially if you factor in shipping costs.
I did okay with cheap knockoffs, though, in Lazada/Shoppee.
In fact, I still have the one I used to open Isya&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other plastic prying tools may be needed.
They can be bought on the cheap at your favorite e-commerce site.
Look up with terms like &amp;ldquo;plastic prying tools for electronics&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tweezer&#34;&gt;Tweezer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not included in the picture above, sorry about that.
This will come in handy when putting back the battery ribbon to its slot.
More on this later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;video-tutorial&#34;&gt;Video Tutorial&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have done this (again) without the help of a guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found Everson Siqueira&amp;rsquo;s video, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/4AF1Pjbwc6c&#34;&gt;iPod Classic upgrade: new battery + SD Card. 256GB 7th gen iPod Classic&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;  (YouTube link) really helpful.
I will be referring to this video a few times in this post.
In addition to his tutorial, he also discussed the hurdles he had to overcome so viewers may not repeat his mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also provided an &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/2NpjDTD&#34;&gt;iPod Classic opening reference card in PDF&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (Dropbox link) so I would know where to locate the metal clips that hold together the iPod chassis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;patience&#34;&gt;Patience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of it.
As I said, iPods are not easy to pry open.
That special flexible prying tool mentioned above is key (almost literally) to successfully opening the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say that opening is the hardest part.
The rest will be easy, if not manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is your first time opening an iPod, take your time.
Go over your chosen guide (or video tutorial) again as long as you need to.
It&amp;rsquo;s better to make sure, than force something  and then breaking it needlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my second time doing this, so I&amp;rsquo;m more confident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;swapping-the-hard-drives&#34;&gt;Swapping the Hard Drives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we will be discussing the steps involved in taking out the old hard drive to be replaced with the new solid state one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-open-the-ipod&#34;&gt;1. Open the iPod&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi2.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;an image of ipod and a small roll of washi tape below it&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Washi tape marks the locations of the metal clips&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the aid Siqueira&amp;rsquo;s iPod Classing opening reference, I used washi tape to indicate the locations of the metal clips&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that hold together the iPod.
I did this, because I have no printer to have the PDF printed.
To be as accurate as possible, I aligned the iPod with the image on the PDF, making sure that it is zoomed to actual size, before placing the markings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I inserted the flexible metal prying tool in between the seams at the edge, following the marked locations.
I disengaged first the top clip, then the two bottom clips.
Disengaging the clips on both sides can be done after, either by alternating between each side, or doing all in one side first before going to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll reiterate:
Refer to the video tutorial first on how exactly this is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-disconnecting-the-battery-ribbon&#34;&gt;2. Disconnecting the battery ribbon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi3.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;an opened ipod&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Disconnecting the battery ribbon&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After successfully disengaging all clips, flip the iPod so it is facing down on your work surface.
Slowly carefully lift the back chassis.
metal-clips shouldn&amp;rsquo;t open it wide yet, because there&amp;rsquo;s a battery ribbon still connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a plastic prying tool, slide up the black plastic clip that holds the battery ribbon.
The battery ribbon can now be lifted (carefully) up, still with the help of a prying tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi4.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;an opened ipod&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Freshly opened iPod. LEFT: Back metal shell, battery (the yellow-orange rectangle); RIGHT: Front chassis, and what you&amp;rsquo;re seeing is the mechanical hard drive and some foam&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPod is now open.
Relish this moment of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that there&amp;rsquo;s still one ribbon connected to the front chassis.
This is for the headphones jack.
Keep it in tact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battery still has some significant juice in it, so that&amp;rsquo;s an upgrade for another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-disconnect-the-original-hard-drive&#34;&gt;3. Disconnect the original hard drive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original hard drive is attached to the motherboard via flexible flat cable (FFC) through called a Zero Insertion Force (ZIF) connector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi5.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;an opened ipod&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Disconnecting the HDD&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the side of the hard drive, there&amp;rsquo;s a sliver of black plastic flap that must first be flipped to disengage the FFC from the ZIF.
Do that carefully with a plastic prying tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once disengaged, the hard drive shall be easy to pull off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi6.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;an opened ipod and a mechanical hard disk&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;RIGHTMOST: Hard drive successfully removed&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-installing-the-new-solid-state-drive&#34;&gt;4. Installing the new solid state drive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solid state drive here, technically, is the microSD.
Insert it in one of the slots in the iFlash-Quad adapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adapter comes with a small square foam, with an adhesive side.
This will act as a spacer between the adapter and the iPod&amp;rsquo;s circuit board.
The adapter being thinner than the original hard drive, the foam provides a snug fit, so the iPod won&amp;rsquo;t be an overpriced maracas.
Refer to the following image to know which side the foam must be placed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi7.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;image of iFlash solid state drive&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;iFlash-Quad, with foams&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connect the FFC to adapter&amp;rsquo;s on-board ZIF connector.
It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be hard to slide it in.
If the FFC is somewhat resisting, be sure that it is evenly sliding in, not at an angle.
Then, lock it in by putting the black plastic flap back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the following image to see the orientation of the adapter during connection.
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi8.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;an opened ipod&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Installing the solid state drive&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-closing-the-ipod&#34;&gt;5. Closing the iPod&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realign the back chassis back to the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a tweezer (pictured in the following image), reconnect the battery ribbon in the same slot as before.
Lock it in by pushing down the black plastic slider.
Give it a light tug to ensure that it isn&amp;rsquo;t loosely connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/mi9.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;an opened ipod&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Reconnecting the battery ribbon&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press some buttons to check first if the iPod is turning on.
Under normal circumstances, it should.
If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, trying recharging it.
If during the process of opening the iPod, you somehow damaged it that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn on, it&amp;rsquo;s beyond the scope of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPod is now ready to be closed.
While making sure the back is aligned to the front chassis, push down on the metal.
Clicks should be heard;
the metals clips are now engaged and the iPod is locked closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;then-comes-the-music&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;then comes the music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the iPod should feel snappier and lighter, because it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;rsquo;ve replaced the massive energy drain which was the original hard drive, battery should last a bit longer.
Accessing the memory isn&amp;rsquo;t done mechanically, unlike the original hard drive, which literally needed to spin a disk (where the whirring sound comes from).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connect the iPod to a computer (ideally a Mac, but Windows or GNU+Linux would be fine) with iTunes installed on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPod will be prompted for a restore, and then a software update.
Do these both via iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When successfully done, the iPod can now sync with iTunes, so make sure you packed the latter with decent muzak.
They syncing process is outside the scope of this post, but it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too hard.
Look it up online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iPod Classic, 6th Generation (&amp;ldquo;7th gen&amp;rdquo; in some sites), 2nd revision, 160 GB capacity, Model No. A1238.
For more info on iPods, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPod_Classic&#34;&gt;check the wikipedia about it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to call ourselves &lt;a href=&#34;https://arawseekers.github.io&#34;&gt;Araw Seekers&lt;/a&gt;.
You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to go over there and read. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One would notice the absence of screws with which to open the device.
Instead, there are metal clips on the inside all around the edge.
Without prior knowledge, one would think that the iPod was not designed to be maintained, and one would be right in thinking so. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encoding: From Hardcopy to Softcopy</title>
      <link>/encode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 16:48:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/encode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;statusDone&#34; id=&#34;status-done&#34;&gt;Status: Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, I decided to help Isya on encoding a lot of documents from a family friend, Tito Jorge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an attempt to document the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope-of-work&#34;&gt;Scope of Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documents that we&amp;rsquo;re talking about here are printed articles written by Tito Jorge.
He&amp;rsquo;s quite the writer, so each article easily goes above 4,000 words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are tasked to convert these printed materials into a Word document (docx) as softcopies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial suggestion was to manually typewrite &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;.
Surely, though, there must be a smarter way to make softcopies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scanning-of-documents&#34;&gt;Scanning of Documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we have no scanner in our home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I used the Adobe Scan app on the iPhone that I still had.
It&amp;rsquo;s fine.
I just had to make sure that the text in each scanned page was readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scanned files are in PDF format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I AirDropped the scanned files to Isya&amp;rsquo;s MacBook, because that&amp;rsquo;s where I would be working on them.
AirDrop is limited to Apple devices;
it&amp;rsquo;s Apple&amp;rsquo;s fancy way of transferring files over bluetooth.
The magic lies in how incredibly fast the transfer time is, even in large batches of files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, one doesn&amp;rsquo;t need Apple devices to do these.
Just remember that the important things here are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a way to scan the documents; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a way to transfer them to the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;converting-pdf-to-docx&#34;&gt;Converting PDF to docx&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to make use of free online software.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be needing Optical Character Recognition (OCR) software for this one, particularly one that can convert PDF to docx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.onlineocr.net&#34;&gt;Free Online OCR&lt;/a&gt;, simply because it&amp;rsquo;s the topmost item in the search list.
What I will discuss next is based on that platform.
You can choose other websites, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to figure it out yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Free Online OCR landing page, you can do a quick task of converting PDF to docx.
However, you&amp;rsquo;ll soon find out that this will only output the first page of the document.
The max file size is also limited to 15 MB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase these numbers, you need to sign up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sign-up-on-free-online-ocr-using-disposable-email&#34;&gt;Sign up on Free Online OCR using disposable email&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never use your own personal email account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many free online services that provide disposable emails.
For this, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://temp-mail.org&#34;&gt;Temp Mail&lt;/a&gt; which &amp;ldquo;provides temporary, secure, anonymous, free, disposable email address.&amp;rdquo;
Keep this tab (or window) open for as long you need this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you click SIGN UP on the upper right of the page, you will be prompted to fill up a form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter username: &lt;code&gt;[enter any gibberish]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Enter password&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: &lt;code&gt;[enter any gibberish]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Confirm password: &lt;code&gt;[same as above]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Enter E-mail: &lt;code&gt;[Copy the email from Temp Mail]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Enter Captcha code: &lt;code&gt;[captcha code here]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;del&gt;blindly&lt;/del&gt; accept the Terms of Service and Privacy Policy in the checkbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log in once you&amp;rsquo;ve successfully signed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logging in increases your wiggle room, namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;max file size is bumped up to 200 MB;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;max number of pages is now 50;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plus some other options that you might find useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you deplete the number of available pages, which you will if you&amp;rsquo;re working on a lot academic articles, just create another account, with the help of Temp Mail!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating another account, be sure to delete the cookies in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to download all the docx files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;polish-the-documents&#34;&gt;Polish the documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, all the files are now in docx format.
The OCR converter will have tried its best in recognizing the text, tables, and even images.
The quality of the converted docx will greatly depend on the scanning process, but even then, the final output won&amp;rsquo;t be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open your favorite word processor.
I used Microsoft Word in the MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most labor-intensive part of the whole process which includes these things to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check the spelling;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check the punctuation marks;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check the formatting;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recreate the data tables, if need be;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rescan and include any important images;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have processed about 133 pages of scholarly articles, done in about 13 hours (non-continuous).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;Recommendation/s&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To future-proof the articles, it would be nice to convert them also to plaintext (txt).
Plaintext ensures that it can be ported to other computers and platforms, while eating as little memory space as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plaintext can be formatted with Markdown.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pandoc.org&#34;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt; is a universal converter, and free software at that, that can be used to covnert txt (or markdown) to, say, docx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re the kind who handwrites on their journal, you may want to keep a digital backup of your personal musings by implementing what I discussed above.
Take note (ha!) of the legibility of your handwriting;
the OCR might not recognize your cursive penmanship!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps, you own a distraction-free, old-but-working-still typewriter?
Type your thoughts in a distraction-free machine&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, scan, and edit and/or finalize the digital copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To easily come up with a password, this would be the best time to start using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacytools.io/software/passwords/#pw&#34;&gt;password manager&lt;/a&gt;.
Most of the password managers have randomizers, which prints out random strings of alphanumeric characters, that you can simply copy and paste. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://typewriterrevolution.com/manifesto&#34;&gt;Typewriter Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re into that. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always Carry A Book Website</title>
      <link>/alwayscarry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 15:02:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alwayscarry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;statusOnGoing&#34; id=&#34;status-on-going&#34;&gt;Status: On-going&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My partner has asked me to come up with a website to act as a central hub for their recently opened online bookshop.
This site shall mirror the contents of the shop&amp;rsquo;s other social media presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the site, whose name I also came up with:
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alwayscarry.netlify.app&#34;&gt;Always Carry A Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/acabooks.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;screenshot from Always Carry A Book website &#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Screenshot from the website&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-choices&#34;&gt;Design Choices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured that since this would just be a small online shop, a full-blown e-commerce site with lots of features is unnecessary.
Having this in mind, I decided that a static site would do.
Since I&amp;rsquo;m already familiar with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, I use it as my static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business is literally just starting out.
One major decision is to use free software services for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the intention is to scale, and add the necessary functions as the business starts raking in the dough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;landing-page-logo&#34;&gt;Landing Page Logo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cat-holding-a-book image is drawn by Isya herself, using Wacom Bamboo Tablet on &lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org&#34;&gt;Krita&lt;/a&gt;, a free and open source painting program, that&amp;rsquo;s also available in many platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image, compressed and optimized for the web, shall be the guiding aesthetic of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;payment-gateway&#34;&gt;Payment Gateway?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s only natural for an e-commerce site to have a payment method coded in it.
However, right now, it has no integrated payment gateways like PayPal, Stripe, or others, in the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Payment will be made in &amp;ldquo;less convenient&amp;rdquo; ways, by employing other known services like GCash, PayMaya, and the traditional Bank Transfer.
In my opinion, these methods, particularly the first two, will reach more people since neither need debit nor credit card to make transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Forms is also used for the customers to fill up when placing their orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, this will have to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;integration-with-instagram&#34;&gt;Integration with Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to reach as many prospects as possible, the shop is also available in Instagram and Facebook.
We&amp;rsquo;re thinking of focusing a huge chunk of content management via IG.
Each post will then appear on the Facebook Page, and on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a brilliant idea to use Hugo&amp;rsquo;s native integration with Instagram through their API, according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#instagram&#34;&gt;Hugo&amp;rsquo;s documentation&lt;/a&gt;.
The first try, though, it already failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out, the Instagram shortcode is deprecated since 24 Oct 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gohugoio/hugo/issues/7879&#34;&gt;according to this discussion.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good thing that from that same discussion, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gohugoio/hugo/issues/7879#issuecomment-737149676&#34;&gt;monsieurnebo&amp;rsquo;s fix&lt;/a&gt; (based on ToniTornado, but with a bit smaller code) got it going for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time being, I can use the IG photo&amp;rsquo;s ID to be embedded on the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hosting-github--netlify&#34;&gt;Hosting: GitHub + Netlify&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source files are on GitHub. The HTML files are then deployed to Netlify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make the changes (edit, generate the site, etc.) locally, in a laptop.
These changes are then committed and pushed to the GitHub repository.
Finally, I have set up Netlify to detect the changes from the repository, and the site is deployed for public viewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;search-functionality&#34;&gt;Search Functionality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we upload more content, i.e. more books, the list grows.
I have added a search bar in the list page to help visitors, using JavaScript.
This is based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://zwbetz.com/add-search-functionality-to-your-blog-listing-page/&#34;&gt;zwbetz&amp;rsquo;s tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I may have implied &lt;a href=&#34;/site/#no-javascript&#34;&gt;a slight distaste for JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, but since we intend this to be an e-commerce site, we have to be in a different mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the user types a letter in the search bar, items with matching string of text remain, incrementally narrowing down the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JavaScript function is actually an Immediately Invoked Function Expression&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and it runs as soon as it is defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JavaScript code can either be wrapped in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags at the end of the HTML page of the book list;
or it can be separate file, like &lt;code&gt;search.js&lt;/code&gt; living in the &lt;code&gt;your-hugo-site/static/js/search.js&lt;/code&gt; directory which can then be invoked using Hugo Partials&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
For posterity, here&amp;rsquo;s the JS code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; () {
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;updateCount&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;) {
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;listCount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; document.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;list-count&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;listCount&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;innerText&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Count: &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;;
  }

  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;onEvent&lt;/span&gt;() {
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;search&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;toUpperCase&lt;/span&gt;();
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; document.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;list&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;listItems&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;getElementsByTagName&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;li&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;listItems&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;) {
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;listItems&lt;/span&gt;[&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;];
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;innerText&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;toUpperCase&lt;/span&gt;();
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;indexOf&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;) {
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;display&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;;
      } &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;display&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;none&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;;
      }
    }
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;updateCount&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;);
  }

  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;search&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; document.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;search&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;search&lt;/span&gt;) {
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;search&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;keyup&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;onEvent&lt;/span&gt;);
  }
})();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-a-transaction-looks-like&#34;&gt;How A Transaction Looks Like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I outline the processes involved for the customer and the dealer.
This is not final, and obviously needs more thought put into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;customer-side&#34;&gt;Customer Side&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer browses the book list, and makes a selection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer fills up the Form, giving us the needed details of the order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer waits for the invoice.
Ideally, it arrives within 24 hours.
When the invoice is confirmed to have been received, this informs the customer that their order is reserved under their name for the next 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer pays within 24 hours of receiving the invoice.
Otherwise, the reservation is revoked, and the order is made available again for the public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once payment is verified, the order will be packed and sent.
Customer&amp;rsquo;s waiting duration depends on the delivery option they chose in the Form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer tracks the package until they receive it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer receives the package, and the transaction is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dealer-side-we-the-sellers&#34;&gt;Dealer Side (&lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt;, the sellers)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We check the Google Form at least once a day for any orders made.
We also check our other inboxes (Facebook, Instagram, and Gmail) for any inquiries people might have for us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will process orders in a first-come-first-serve basis.
This means that an order will be given to the next one in line if the one before failed to pay within 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We send the invoice to the customer.
This will also let them know that the order is reserved under their name for the next 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If payment is made, we will start packing.
Else, as mentioned, it is made available again, or is given to the next customer who intended to order it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After packing, the package is sent via the chosen courier.
The number of waiting days depends on customer&amp;rsquo;s location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We track the package and give updates to the customer until they receive it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the customer receives the package, the transaction is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dropping-content&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Dropping&amp;rsquo; Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current way involves a lot of friction on our side, to be honest.
This is one of the drawbacks of going static: doing things &amp;ldquo;manually.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s enumerate the steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The files, mainly photos of books to be sold, live in the laptop&amp;mdash;a MacBook, and are backed up in a OneDrive account.
The phone can then access the photos via the cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, to save on bandwidth, we can transfer over a USB connection, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.android.com/filetransfer/&#34;&gt;Android File Transfer&lt;/a&gt; as the needed middleman.
The operative word is &amp;ldquo;needed,&amp;rdquo; because one cannot &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; plug an Android phone into a Mac and be done with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the phone, images will be uploaded on Instagram.
Since the IG account is already linked to the FB Page, each post shall simultaneously pop up on both platforms.
&lt;em&gt;In theory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once posted, we will get the photo ID for each IG post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the ID, we can now embed the IG post on the website, thanks to the workaround mentioned earlier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;taking-photos&#34;&gt;Taking Photos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo-taking is done during daytime, when we make use of natural light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, we used an iPhone to take photos of the books.
Transferring files between Apple devices (in our case, iPhone and Mac) is easy, using AirDrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for reasons that won&amp;rsquo;t be mentioned, the iPhone is sure to be removed from the equation.
We need to find solutions that don&amp;rsquo;t rely on AirDrop&amp;rsquo;s convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have two options left: a digital camera, and an Android phone, the same one where we will be posting on IG.
For better quality photos, the digital camera is the obvious choice.
Its SD Card will also fit nicely in one of the Mac&amp;rsquo;s ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phone&amp;rsquo;s camera will serve as a backup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;syndication-of-posts&#34;&gt;Syndication of Posts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If embedding posts from IG would fail somehow in the future, we could just post directly on the website.
Right now, as mentioned, we focus the content management in IG due to its reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Glossary/IIFE&#34;&gt;Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s explainer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partials are smaller, context-aware components in your list and papge templates that can be used economically to keep your templating DRY (&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Repeat Yourself&amp;rdquo;).
For more info, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/partials/#readout&#34;&gt;read the Hugo documentation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Own Web Server</title>
      <link>/server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 22:37:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;statusOpen&#34; id=&#34;status-open&#34;&gt;Status: Open&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to host this very site you&amp;rsquo;re in in a server that I own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, a server is just like any other computer, with lots of functionalities, like providing services or serving files to other computers (clients, as they are called in this context) that access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my use case, I will use it to host the HTML files of this site, and serve it to you, visitors, through your device/s (clients).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server will actually be an old laptop that&amp;rsquo;s just lying around here.
And it&amp;rsquo;s not actually mine.
The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.laptopmag.com/reviews/laptops/msi-wind-u123&#34;&gt;MSI Wind Netbook&lt;/a&gt; belongs to Isya, and I got her permission to use it for this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;specifications-of-the-machine&#34;&gt;Specifications of the Machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth 2.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU: 1.66-GHZ Intel Atom N280&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display size: 10.2&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphics card: Intel GMA 950&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard drive size: 80Gb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard drive speed: 5,400rpm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard drive type: SATA hard drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native resolution: 1024x600&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating system (OS, default): MS Windows XP Home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ports (excluding USB): VGA, Microphone, Headphone, Ethernet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RAM: 2Gb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weight: 1.45 kg (3.2 lbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wifi: 802.11b/g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;its-old&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s old&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By today&amp;rsquo;s standards, it&amp;rsquo;s an old machine.
If the numbers don&amp;rsquo;t make sense to you, just look at the OS:
it shipped with Windows XP!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the day, Windows XP received many praises for its performance.
These days, though, it&amp;rsquo;s vulnerable to a lot of cyberattacks, more so that &lt;a href=&#34;www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/windows/end-of-windows-xp-support&#34;&gt;Microsoft has stopped supporting it since 2014&lt;/a&gt;.
And yet, some institutions still use it.
If their computers are connected to the Internet, they are exposed to black hat hackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/msi-wind.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;screenshot of the laptop&amp;#39;s system properties&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;And now, a crappy photo of the laptop&amp;rsquo;s system properties&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;-but-works-fine&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip; but works fine.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because it&amp;rsquo;s old doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s no longer valuable.
For its age, its quick to boot up.
It would likely improve if and when the hard drive is replaced with a solid state drive, although, doing so is really unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its current state, it &amp;ldquo;runs out of breath&amp;rdquo; trying to run modern applications with its very limiting hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next best thing is to refurbish it into something that isn&amp;rsquo;t resource intensive.
This project will also be a learning process for me on how to manage my own small server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-suitable-operating-system&#34;&gt;A suitable operating system&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To many system administrators (sysadmin), a suitable operating system (OS) could mean many different things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no sysadmin by profession, so the OS I want running in this homebrew server shall be stable, requires minimal maintenance, and is (relatively) easy to set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t require much effort, knowing that my use case&amp;mdash;serving static files of small personal website&amp;mdash;is simple enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I&amp;rsquo;m considering these two OS, because they still have support for 32-bit architectures (which this laptop has), and meet my requirements above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; (GNU+Linux)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openbsd.org&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; (BSD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have experience in using both, albeit in a 64-bit architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-openbsd-as-a-server&#34;&gt;Using OpenBSD as a server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBSD is a fully functional, Unix-like OS based on Berkeley Networking Release 2 (Net/2) and 4.4BSD-Lite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I choose OpenBSD as a server because it&amp;rsquo;s simpler to set up.
As a result of its simplicity, it&amp;rsquo;s also hailed as one of the most secure OS out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before anything else, a disclaimer:
While I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to update this document, assume that the most recent documentation there is can be found over at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://openbsd.org&#34;&gt;OpenBSD website&lt;/a&gt;.
Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://man.openbsd.org&#34;&gt;manual pages&lt;/a&gt; contain the details needed to operate a machine running on OpenBSD, and is entirely available offline on a base install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-openbsd-on-bare-metal&#34;&gt;Installing OpenBSD on bare metal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to the system, I highly recommend to go over the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/faq4.html&#34;&gt;OpenBSD FAQ - Installation Guide&lt;/a&gt; at least once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m installing from a Debian-based system, through the terminal, so most of the commands here are based on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-download-the-installer&#34;&gt;1. Download the installer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are mirrors&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from which you can download the installer.
They are found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openbsd.org/ftp.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Always choose the one nearest your location to reduce download time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -OJ http://mirror.rise.ph/pub/OpenBSD/6.8/i386/install68.img
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-create-install-media-in-flash-drive&#34;&gt;2. Create Install Media in Flash Drive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plug in the USB stick.
The following command assumes that the disk is recognized as &lt;code&gt;sdc1&lt;/code&gt;.
Check with &lt;code&gt;dmesg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;df -h&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;lsblk&lt;/code&gt; commands, as root if need be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dd if=install*.img of=/dev/sdc1 bs=1M
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; utility copies the standard input &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; (or input file) to the standard output &lt;code&gt;of&lt;/code&gt; (or output file, which, in this case, is the USB drive).
&lt;code&gt;bs&lt;/code&gt; stands for block size, and we set it to 1 megabyte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, the successful output is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;450+0 records in
450+0 records out
471859200 bytes (472 MB, 450 MiB) copied, 31.9492 s, 14.8 MB/s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-up-wi-fi-and-ethernet-networks&#34;&gt;Set up wi-fi and ethernet networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-server-on-openbsd&#34;&gt;Web Server on OpenBSD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-httpd8&#34;&gt;Configure httpd(8)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enable-https-with-acme-client1-and-lets-encrypt&#34;&gt;Enable HTTPS with acme-client(1) and Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;add-http-security-headers-with-relayd8&#34;&gt;Add HTTP security headers with relayd(8)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just a server that provides the exact copy of data from another server.
Usually to provide a means of redundancy. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Site: Colophon</title>
      <link>/site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 14:42:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;statusOnGoing&#34; id=&#34;status-on-going&#34;&gt;Status: On-going&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The making of this site is itself a personal project.
Here in this oversized Colophon I will discuss how and, most importantly, why this all was conceived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;digital-garden&#34;&gt;Digital Garden&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been looking around for personal websites like I have, &amp;ldquo;digital garden&amp;rdquo; is a phrase that gets used often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is where webmasters carefully plant the seeds of ideas, and hope to grow them sustainably.
It&amp;rsquo;s a more endearing term, I believe, than, say, a public-facing journal or simply blog.
They all function the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site, then, is my digital garden.
Expect that things will be corrected, deleted, edited, fed, &lt;em&gt;grown&lt;/em&gt;, depending on any number of factors, including the current state of things.
People change (they need to, lest they stagnate), and every fiber of their being changes with them, literally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;public-repository-of-independent-research&#34;&gt;Public Repository of Independent Research&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of ideas, I will use this site as a publishing platform of the results of my research, if any at all.
I am going the more &amp;ldquo;progressive&amp;rdquo; route of bypassing the traditional way to PhD.
After reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://nadiaeghbal.com&#34;&gt;Nadia Eghbal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nadiaeghbal.com/phd&#34;&gt;Reimagining the PhD&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m now more inclined to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t also imagine spending at least three years getting a master&amp;rsquo;s degree, holding on to the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;necessary&amp;rdquo; to further my career.
I am, more or less, happy with the opportunity cost of not dealing with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of going through the application process for post-graduate studies, may I now enlist you, Dear Public, as my peer reviewer?
I hope you don&amp;rsquo;t mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never liked receiving rejection emails, but I get that they&amp;rsquo;re needed, in that they let me know that I can go on with other applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least, through this site, I (hopefully) wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be receiving (unsolicited) rejection letters from anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, having the public as my peer reviewer, I think, opens interesting avenues for the stakeholders (me and the public).
There will always be people smarter than me.
Hopefully, I can pull some of their attention here to share their insights someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this online space, let&amp;rsquo;s assume that nothing is set to stone.
Through editing, I&amp;rsquo;m able to improve a body of content.
I can learn by doing, and sharing the entire process with you as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;major-sections&#34;&gt;Major Sections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is divided into two main sections: &lt;strong&gt;Log&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Projects&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Log, more than anything else, is a changelog of what has evolved since the last update.
It mainly captures the significant revisions in the busiest parts of the Site, which would be the Projects.
Each Log will start with a changelog.
After that, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to incorporate some personal skits, in an attempt to add character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Projects is a list of the thing/s I&amp;rsquo;m currently pursuing.
Each one begins with Table of Contents (ToC), so that readers will have an overview of the topics ahead.
Readers can click each topic in the ToC if they feel like jumping to that part already.
The write-ups will be a healthy blend of creative and technical writing, to prevent you from getting bored, something I won&amp;rsquo;t afford to do in a formal setting.
Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ll include citations properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RSS feed, which tracks only the Log (which, as mentioned, tracks all the changes anyway), is a whole separate thing.
I don&amp;rsquo;t consider it a section of this site, though.
It&amp;rsquo;s only a link that you can copy and paste on your favorite RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the modern email clients like Thunderbird, Microsoft Outlook, and Apple Mail, have their own built-in RSS reader, so you can use that as well, especially if you do the majority of your reading in an email client.
A web service is available along these lines: check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://rssby.email&#34;&gt;RSS by email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;front-end&#34;&gt;Front-end&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you are well aware, this site has a very simple design.
Admittedly, it&amp;rsquo;s the result of having only a working knowledge of HTML and CSS, and none of JavaScript.
It turns out that this is a feature, not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By foregoing intricate UI/UX design, I can focus on what matters most: &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt;.
Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By simplifying the design, I&amp;rsquo;m making this site less bloated.
This means that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low-end and/or old computers with slow and/or outdated software can visit with little to no hassle on their end;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;locations with poor internet connectivity can still browse the content;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can also improve this site&amp;rsquo;s accessibility by improving layout, among many other things;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the site loads fast because of no tracking, no custom fonts; and,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no distractions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;link-management&#34;&gt;Link Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links in this site that have a greenish northeast arrow (&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;\2197&lt;/code&gt;&amp;quot;) right after them are external links, i.e. links that take the visitor out of this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In CSS, I implented this using a selector that finds all links other than my own, which is &lt;code&gt;oqolarte.github.io&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;oqolarte.github.io&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;^=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;mailto&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;^=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;#&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;^=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;after&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34; &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;; 
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;green&lt;/span&gt;;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;display&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;inline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;block&lt;/span&gt;;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above snippet means that if a link does not contain &lt;code&gt;oqolarte.github.io&lt;/code&gt;, a same-page anchor link (e.g. #status), &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; an internal website (e.g. /project), then &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; will be displayed &lt;code&gt;after&lt;/code&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, these arrows only indicate external links to let visitors know that they will be directed away.
Clicking one does &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; open it in a new tab.
You have to manually right-click it and select &lt;code&gt;Open in a new tab&lt;/code&gt; (or click with Mouse3/MouseWheel).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-javascript&#34;&gt;No JavaScript?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/image/nojs.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;screenshot from estimator dot dev evaluating this site as no javascript detected&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Look, ma! No JS, according to estimator.dev!&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not really that I find JS harmful, although some would argue that it could be.
I don&amp;rsquo;t even know enough of the language to make that claim.
In fact, I used JS to &lt;a href=&#34;/alwayscarry/#search-functionality&#34;&gt;add a search functionality on small bookshop website&lt;/a&gt; I volunteered to create for Isya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why this &amp;ldquo;distaste&amp;rdquo; for JS in websites?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the simple layout, the interactions with the visitor are limited to clicking links, which my site can practically do without JavaScript.
It&amp;rsquo;s absence is definitely beneficial, because there&amp;rsquo;s less code to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-ads&#34;&gt;No Ads&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only marketers like ads&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
Good thing that I have none of them here.
And I don&amp;rsquo;t intend to put them here anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, did you know that a lot of online advertising you see depends on JS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;images&#34;&gt;Images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans can be very visual &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt;.
In the internet, however, we must play it differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big image size takes time to load, and will of course need more resources to serve it to the visitor.
More resources mean more energy consumed means larger carbon footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding images to a site, I make sure that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; tell &amp;ldquo;more than a thousand words.&amp;rdquo;
An image must add to the narrative, not distract the viewers away from it.
If it it&amp;rsquo;s not adding value content-wise, it&amp;rsquo;s not going in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s compressed as much as possible, to reduce its size, minimizing the time it takes to load.
There are several tools you can use to do this.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tinyjpg.com&#34;&gt;Tiny JPG&lt;/a&gt; is an online image compression tool, in which you can upload up to 20 image files, max 5MB each.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, I  tend to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jarun/imgp&#34;&gt;imgp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, a &amp;ldquo;high-performance cli batch image resizer and rotator,&amp;rdquo; that I can use offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the command line, I do something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;imgp -x 1366x0 --quality=85 -pew ~/image.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-x&lt;/code&gt; is output resolution in HRESxVRES (horizontal and vertical resolution respectively).
Here, I set HRES = 1366, and VRES will adapt to maintain the ratio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--quality&lt;/code&gt; is the quality factor.
Here, I set it to 85.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-pew&lt;/code&gt; combines three options: optimize, erase EXIF metadata&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and overwrite source images respectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-end&#34;&gt;Back-end&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; static site generator to build this site.
There are many other big names out there, like Jekyll, Gatsby, Pelican, and Hexo, but I have no experience using them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-name-of-static-site-generator-ssg&#34;&gt;In the name of Static Site Generator (SSG)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using SSG like Hugo arguably increases security by simplifying a lot of things.
There is no server-side software to install, no database to keep up to date, and no PHP plugins to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the content is written in Markdown, a simple markup &amp;ldquo;language&amp;rdquo; for creating formatted text using a plaintext editor.
This means that all the files are lightweight and portable, easy to backup and transfer between computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compilation is fast.
Since web browsers can only read HTML files, compilation means that SSG converts the Markdown files into HTML.
And if you&amp;rsquo;re like me whose website comprises only HTML and CSS files, compilation can average on 100ms (milliseconds!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might sound tedious, because it is at first!
Unlike what-you-see-is-what-you-get (WYSIWYG) CMS like Wordpress in which you can easily post a new blog, with SSGs, you will have to, at least, type your post offline, compile, and then push to your web host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ll take the massive freedom gains provided by SSGs&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; anytime!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-hugo&#34;&gt;Using Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of tutorials online on how to start a blog using Hugo.
A lot of them, if you follow to the letter, will set you up a nice content management system (CMS, a fancier, more technical term for blog).
But many of these tutorials are naturally targetted to beginners who just want to get something up already, and not go through hours of laboriously reading through the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want something that isn&amp;rsquo;t pre-fabricated, some template that can&amp;rsquo;t be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/a&gt;, a theme that speaks your personality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s when you need to read the docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, Hugo&amp;rsquo;s learning curve is steep, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re like me with no &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; coding experience.
Maybe it helps when you&amp;rsquo;ve been dealing with software programming for a while.
Your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with everything else, it&amp;rsquo;s important to be patient and willing to read the documentation.
Some documentations are good, some are bad, some don&amp;rsquo;t even exist!
In any case, you can also ask the community if you&amp;rsquo;re stuck somewhere.
Hugo has a decent documentation&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My process involves a lot of trial and error to get this site looking the way it is now, simple as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, though, Hugo may be too complex of a generator for a simple website such as this one.
But we&amp;rsquo;ll see.
It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m already familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disabling-internal-templates&#34;&gt;Disabling Internal Templates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo ships with internal templates that I have disabled because they either violate privacy, will add unnecessary bloat to the site, or both. They are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disqus comments, a popular commenting system;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram cards;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter cards;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vimeo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have a privacy-centered configuration, I followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/&#34;&gt;this documentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/#disable-all-services&#34;&gt;disabled all services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in high school, I&amp;rsquo;m not the brightest pupil in our computer lab, and I&amp;rsquo;m okay with that.
One of our &amp;ldquo;lab works&amp;rdquo; was to create our own website.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how mine looked, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s basic, with broken links hither and thither.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a decade later, here I am, building one again.
At least I retained the important bits on how HTML works, so I&amp;rsquo;m not starting from zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to say that I dedicate this to my former self, who couldn&amp;rsquo;t seem to grasp the importance of web design.
Even today, I can only rely on Hugo, a working knowledge in HTML and CSS, and a little bit of patience to set everything up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some other sites from which I got inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low-tech Magazine, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com&#34;&gt;solar-powered one&lt;/a&gt;. Their article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2018/09/how-to-build-a-lowtech-website.html&#34;&gt;how to build a low-tech website&lt;/a&gt; is eye-opening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://1mb.club&#34;&gt;1MB Club&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s contemporaries, &lt;a href=&#34;https://512kb.club&#34;&gt;512KB Club&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://250kb.club&#34;&gt;250KB Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bestmotherfucking.website&#34;&gt;Best Motherfucking Website&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://danluu.com&#34;&gt;Dan Luu&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;, although it might need a few tweaks to improve readability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-do&#34;&gt;To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a wishlist of sorts that I need to do for this site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Purchase a proper domain name for this site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Move away from GitHub Pages and host somewhere else, &lt;a href=&#34;/server/&#34;&gt;preferably on a machine I own&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Have TLS certificate, preferably from &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;, because there&amp;rsquo;s really no excuse to use just HTTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Get at least a score of 50 on Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://observatory.mozilla.org/&#34;&gt;HTTP Observatory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all of the items in this (growing) list is ticked off, this TODO segment will be deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s just a wild claim.
I have no proof of it &lt;em&gt;yet&lt;/em&gt;, but absence of evidence doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean evidence of absence, &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;?
Maybe the creatives who are coerced into doing the visuals also like their work. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s available in many Unix-like systems, including Linux distros, and macOS.
Visit their page for more info. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exchangeable image file format (EXIF) metadata is removed to help  reduce the image size.
As an added bonus, it&amp;rsquo;s scrubs the image of details that might divulge unnecessary information to internet strangers when they inspect it, such as data, time, and location the image is created. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamstack.org/generators/&#34;&gt;Jamstack&lt;/a&gt; for a list of hundreds of possible SSGs! &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &amp;ldquo;decent&amp;rdquo; I mean it covers all the basic needs to help you set up a working site.
In its current state, it&amp;rsquo;s reliable.
However, the more complex you make your site, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that Hugo documentation still needs more polishing. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
